<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>7.5 inch on Goosst blog</title>
    <link>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/tags/7.5-inch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 7.5 inch on Goosst blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://users.telenet.be/goosst/tags/7.5-inch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>epaper Home Assistant</title>
      <link>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/posts/homeautomation_epaper_hass/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/posts/homeautomation_epaper_hass/</guid>
      <description>Intro This is the part that will create the content out of home assistant and will get displayed on our e-paper. As an example I will display the expected commute time to work.
Python scripts being defined as a shell_command in configuration.yaml will be used. A simple automation to trigger the python script will be used.
Basis of script We want to make a plot that tells us the expected time of our commute with a graph of the last hour, to see how the time is trending.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>e-paper display ESP32</title>
      <link>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/posts/homeautomation_epaper_esp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/posts/homeautomation_epaper_esp/</guid>
      <description>Intro In this part, a figure, living on the Home Assistant server, will be displayed on a 7.5 inch e-paper using an ESP32-based board.
Used components: 7.5 inch e-paper from Waveshare with Driver HAT ESP32 based development board with battery holder Esp 32: pinout The SPI interface of the ESP32 will be used to control the display. The pins of SPI quickly get confusing:
 Names of the different interfaces of SPI aren&amp;rsquo;t very consistently used (MOSI, SPI D, SD0, SS, CS, SCK, CLK, SD1, &amp;hellip; ) + you have to pay attention to the difference between IO pins and GPIO pins in the ESP32 datasheet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>e-paper display concept</title>
      <link>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/posts/homeautomation_epaper_gen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/posts/homeautomation_epaper_gen/</guid>
      <description>Intro This part sketches the entire flow. I&amp;rsquo;ve changed my method a few times during the creation of this. Mainly because I just stumble upon things in the home assistant documentation, rather than actually finding something when I need it :).
Different steps   Sequence to get home assistant content on e-paper    Relevant references to documentation (I want to find it back myself ;):
 Home Assistant: External files Home Assistant: REST API  Remarks:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>e-paper display Intro</title>
      <link>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/posts/homeautomation_epaper_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/posts/homeautomation_epaper_intro/</guid>
      <description>Intro  E-paper display linked with Home Assistant   --   E-paper display linked with Home Assistant   I wanted a display which:
 does not consume (a lot of) electricity is linked with home-assistant, so I can get useful updates pending the moment of the day can display interesting photos, when I don&amp;rsquo;t want to know the status of my house / surroundings :) doesn&amp;rsquo;t cost an arm and a leg  The result of my tinkering can be seen in the picture above.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>