<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Goosst blog</title>
    <link>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Goosst blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://users.telenet.be/goosst/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Vaillant automation part II</title>
      <link>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/posts/homeautomation_partii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/posts/homeautomation_partii/</guid>
      <description>Intro In this part we&amp;rsquo;ll send commands through the interface of Home Assistant.
There is hassbian, hass.io, homme-assistant itself, &amp;hellip; as you see, it&amp;rsquo;s not confusing at all :). I&amp;rsquo;m using hassbian since at least I know ebusd works in a debian environment on the raspberry pi. I&amp;rsquo;m not familiar with docker (hass.io) and its limitations.
Preparing the Raspberry pi  Follow the Hassbian installation instructions: https://www.home-assistant.io/docs/installation/hassbian/installation/
 Additional installations beside the normal updating, upgrading, setting the time-zone:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vaillant automation ebus</title>
      <link>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/posts/homeautomation_parti/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/posts/homeautomation_parti/</guid>
      <description>Intro In this part we&amp;rsquo;ll connect to the communication bus of the heater and read / write some parameters by manually commanding them via a rapsberry pi (in general, the instructions below work with any computer using debian/ubuntu).
Hardware Ebus adapter We need an ebus adapter for the raspberry to interface with our heater. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to write down all the details, since I can just refer to them:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heating automation - intro</title>
      <link>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/posts/homeautomation_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/posts/homeautomation_intro/</guid>
      <description>Intro I think we all want a more intelligent control over our heating than what the standard thermostat and their time-based settings offer. e.g. Automatically turning the heating off when leaving your home, schedulling the heating to turn on sooner when it&amp;rsquo;s cold, &amp;hellip; .
Disregarding privacy concerns, commercial solutions like Google Nest only seem to support on/off control of the heating. If we want to use proportional/modulated heating for more comfort, at the time of writing the amount of solutions seems very limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Hugo</title>
      <link>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/about-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/about-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Hugo is the world’s fastest framework for building websites. It is written in Go.
It makes use of a variety of open source projects including:
 https://github.com/russross/blackfriday https://github.com/alecthomas/chroma https://github.com/muesli/smartcrop https://github.com/spf13/cobra https://github.com/spf13/viper  Learn more and contribute on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>