<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ebus on Goosst blog</title>
    <link>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/tags/ebus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ebus on Goosst blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://users.telenet.be/goosst/tags/ebus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Heating automation - device tracking</title>
      <link>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/posts/homeautomation_partiiii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/posts/homeautomation_partiiii/</guid>
      <description>Intro Concept Home assistant  Device tracking Identify phone Automate heating based on presence     Intro In this part we&amp;rsquo;ll turn our heating off and on when we leave the house (by detecting presence of our mobile phone).
Concept We&amp;rsquo;ll be checking if the mac-address of our phone is on the wifi network. Based on this we&amp;rsquo;ll do a simple scheduling of our heating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heating automation - read information</title>
      <link>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/posts/homeautomation_partiii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/posts/homeautomation_partiii/</guid>
      <description>Intro Concept  Python script Home assistant Home assistant UI Tip     Intro In this part we&amp;rsquo;ll read parameters from our heater through the interface of Home Assistant and plot them in the UI.
Concept We&amp;rsquo;ll be (mis)using the mqtt protocol to send messages from the ebusd program to Home Assistant (both running on the same raspberry). This sending of messages will be done in a python script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heating automation - set temperatures</title>
      <link>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/posts/homeautomation_partii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/posts/homeautomation_partii/</guid>
      <description>Intro Preparing the Raspberry pi Initial temperature test using Home Assistant  Concept python scripts Home Assistant services  Clean up method  Adapt python scripts User interface Mutual exclusion     Intro In this part we&amp;rsquo;ll:
 install hassbian set our requested room temperature through the interface of Home Assistant.  Preparing the Raspberry pi There is hassbian, hass.io, homme-assistant itself, &amp;hellip; as you see, not confusing at all :).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heating automation - setup hardware and ebus</title>
      <link>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/posts/homeautomation_parti/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/posts/homeautomation_parti/</guid>
      <description>Intro Hardware  Ebus adapter Raspberry pi My setup  Software  Preparing the Raspberry pi  Hassbian Static IP address  install and use ebusd     Intro In this part we&amp;rsquo;ll connect to the communication bus of the heater and read / write some parameters by manually commanding them via a raspberry pi (in general, the instructions below work with any computer using debian/ubuntu).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heating automation - intro</title>
      <link>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/posts/homeautomation_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://users.telenet.be/goosst/posts/homeautomation_intro/</guid>
      <description>Intro Goal Tools Setup    Intro I think we all want a more intelligent control over our heaters than what the standard thermostats have to offer. e.g. Automatically turning the heating off when leaving your home, scheduling the heater to turn on sooner in the morning when it&amp;rsquo;s cold, &amp;hellip; .
Disregarding privacy concerns, commercial solutions like Google Nest only seem to support on/off control of the heating.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>